人人影视
YYeTs.com
原创翻译  双语字幕
仅供学习 禁止用于任何商业盈利行为
更多影视更新
请登陆www.YYeTs.com
翻译：圈圈 西西 Liv 青椒 Silence
翻译：DustD 木浅薰 迷失_绽放
时间轴：信徒 薛定谔的猫 咭鹏鹏
校对：Michael 小萝莉  Liv  迷失_绽放
后期：MythCreator  总监:  苹果果
我叫巴里·艾伦
My name is Barry Allen.
是现今世上速度最快的人
I am the fastest man alive.
我十一岁时  我母亲被杀了
When I was 11, my mother was murdered.
我看到一道闪电
I saw a ball of lightning.
那里面  有个人
Inside the lightning there was a man.
他杀了我妈妈
He killed my mom.
我发誓这不是我干的
I swear to God I didn't do this.
-妈妈呢  -那晚发生的事让人无法相信
- Where's mom? - What happened that night was impossible.
但是一场事故让我也变得令人难以置信
Then an accident made me the impossible.
你陷入了昏迷
You were in a coma.
-昏迷了多久  -九个月
- For how long? - Nine months.
你的肌肉应该萎缩了
Your muscles should be atrophied,
但是却在进行细胞重生
but instead they're in a state of cellular regeneration.
我不是唯一一个受爆炸影响的  是不是
I wasn't the only one affected, was I?
我们一直在寻找其他像你一样的超能力者
We've been searching for other meta humans like yourself.
我一直想更加有所作为
All my life I've wanted to do more.
然后我搞砸了我第一次帮助别人的机会
And the first chance I get to help someone, I screw up.
你所做的好事会远比这些错事更有意义
The good you do must far outweigh the bad.
你不会再在里面待太久了
You're not gonna be in here much longer.
不管杀害妈妈的凶手是谁
Whoever killed mom,
我总算有办法找到他们了
I think I finally have a way to find them.
到这部分我好像应该
This is the part where I'm supposed
做自我介绍了
to do the whole intro thingy.
巴里·艾伦  现今世上速度最快的人
Barry Allen, fastest man alive...
但是这个大家应该都知道了
But you know all that already.
那好  我们就去做点好事吧
All right, let's get to the good stuff.
你看到那里的烟了吗  那是
You see that smoke? That's a fire
中城闹市区西街和第三大街处发生火灾了
on Western and 3rd in downtown Central City.
还有这团疾驰残影  是我正在赶往火灾现场
And that blur? That's me on my way to it.
我现在时速是352英里
I'm going 352 miles an hour.
今天速度真是太慢了
And it's a slow day.
这里是52号云梯队
This is Ladder 52.
还有两分钟才能到达火灾现场
We're still at least two minutes out.
到时候建筑里的人会死的
People are gonna die in there.
我知道
I know.
巴里
Barry?
Barry!
怎么了  跑过了吗
What? Did I miss it?
已经跑过大约六个街区了
You overshot by about six blocks.
怪我
My bad.
佩奇
Paige!
我女儿  有人看到我女儿了吗
My daughter! Has anyone seen my daughter?
佩奇
Paige!
到了吗
You there yet?
你干什么呢
What are you doing?
没什么
Nothing.
你在跟谁说话
Who were you talking to?
-没人啊  -你是在跟巴里说话吧
- No one. - Are you talking to Barry?
-谁  -巴里·艾伦
- Who? - Barry Allen?
被闪电击中  昏迷了九个月
Struck by lighting? Was in a coma for nine months?
醒来之后能跑得比声音传播都快的那个人
Woke up being able to run faster than the speed of sound?
-记起来了吗  -没有
- Ring a bell? - No.
很久没跟他说话了
Haven't talked to him.
西斯科  这里火势很猛
Cisco, there's fire everywhere!
西斯科  你还在吗
Cisco, are you still there?
妈妈
Mom?
Mommy!
妈妈
人都救出来了
Everybody's out.
还有什么吩咐吗  西斯科
What else you got for me, Cisco?
巴里  我是凯特琳
Barry, it's Caitlin.
凯特琳啊
Hey, Caitlin.
你好啊
How's your day?
马上回尖端科研实验室
Get back to S.T.A.R. Labs. Now.
这就回去
On my way.
危险区域
闲人免进
你们俩都疯了吗
Have you both lost your minds?
你们以为自己是谁
Who do you think you are?
我负责眼观六路耳听八方  他负责跑步救人
Well, I'm the eyes and ears, and he's the feet.
一点都不好笑好吗
This isn't funny.
你这样会害死自己的
You could have gotten yourself killed.
你不能跟什么超音速消防员一样
You can't be running around the city
去市里火灾现场救人
like some supersonic fireman.
为什么不行
Why not?
我们不是说过了吗  要用我的速度做好事
This is what we talked about: Me using my speed to do good.
我们说的是你来
We talked about you helping us contain
帮我们控制其他可能
other people who might have been affected
被粒子加速器爆炸影响到的人
by the particle accelerator explosion.
是去对付超能力者
Meta-humans.
除了克莱德·马登  我们还没找到别人
And aside from Clyde Mardon, we haven't found any.
这座城市的人仍然需要帮助
People in this city still need help.
我能帮他们
And I can help them.
我们能帮他们
We can help them.
你能说句话吗
Will you please say something?
我觉得凯特琳的意思是
I think what Caitlin is saying,
她以这种独特的生气方式想说的是
in her own spectacularly angry way,
我们才刚开始理解
is that we are just beginning to understand
你身体的能力
what your body is capable of.
不是我跟你唠叨  艾伦先生
Not to sound like a broken record, Mr. Allen...
我觉得还是谨慎克制为妙
I do caution restraint.
威尔斯博士
Dr. Wells...
你就是因为克制才取得现在的成就吗
I doubt restraint is how you got to be the man you are today.
我现在是坐着轮椅被社会遗弃的人
In a wheelchair and a pariah.
正是因为缺少克制  我才落得如此下场
Lack of restraint is what made me these things.
量力而行
Know your limits.
你弄坏什么的时候
Don't expect me to patch you up
不要每次都指望我帮你
every time you break something.
你去救人的时候发生什么事了吗
Hey, uh... anything happen out there today?
你衣服上的传感器返回了
The sensors in the suit were kicking back
一些奇怪的遥感数据
some weird telemetry,
好像你的身体指数出现了几秒的骤增
like your vitals spiked for a few seconds.
我感觉很好啊
Never felt better.
乔  一切都好吗
Hey, Joe, everything all right?
好极了  我在案发现场
Great. I got a fresh crime scene...
有一具尸体
a dead body...
警探正在询问目击者
detectives interviewing witnesses...
黄色警戒线已经拉好了
Miles of that yellow tape stretched over everything.
只差一个人了  你猜是谁
I'm only missing one thing. Can you guess what that is?
我马上就到
I'll be right there.
工作召唤我了
My day job beckons.
你觉得他要什么时候才会意识到
When do you think he'll realize
他没换衣服
he didn't take his clothes?
罪犯们拿了几把手枪跑了
Perp made off with a bunch of handguns,
至少有六把格洛克19型手枪
at least six Glock 19s.
还有额外的弹夹
Fitted with extra ammunition magazines.
看来有人要准备大干一场啊
Somebody's looking to do a whole lot of bad.
不好意思我来晚了
Hey, sorry I'm late.
给自己买了点秋装啊  艾伦先生
Doing a little fall shopping, Mr. Allen?
我今早出来得太匆忙了  没注意到
I was going so fast this morning, I didn't even notice.
我把监控录像下载下来了
I downloaded the surveillance footage off the video camera.
看起来只有一个罪犯啊
Looks like only one perp.
录像上可能只有一个  但实际上有六个人
Footage may only show one, but it was six guys.
看看这些痕迹  它们都交错在一起
Look, the tracks. They're all crossing each other.
六种脚印  六把枪被盗
Six sets of footprints. Six guns stolen.
这应该是团伙作案
We should be looking for a crew.
真奇怪
Weird.
他们穿的鞋  看起来都是一个鞋码的
The shoes, it looks like they're all the same size.
我猜是男士的十码
Men's tens, I'd guess.
和你的鞋码一样  队长
Just like you, Captain.
不是说你是嫌犯  长官  我
Not that you're a suspect, sir. I--
你一心多用的能力真是令人赞叹
Your ability to multi-task is truly remarkable.
中城警局
你总是能同时让我  队长  还有你自己
The way you can embarrass me, the Captain, and yourself
-都觉得难为情  -乔  我很抱歉
- all at the same time. - Joe, I'm sorry.
你就知道跟我说这句话
I'm starting to think "Joe, I'm sorry" is
我都觉得我的名字是"乔  我很抱歉"了
my actual name considering how often you say it to me.
我要处理的事情太多了
I'm dealing with a lot right now.
我知道你的境地
Look, I know you are.
相信我  我也一样
Believe me, I'm dealing with it, too.
以前我的想法非常简单
I've always had a very simple set of beliefs.
重力让一切东西坠落  水把东西弄湿
Gravity makes things fall. Water makes things wet.
直到几周前  我相信世界上跑得最快的人
And up until a few weeks ago, I believed
跑完一英里需要四分钟
the fastest man could run a mile in four minutes.
而不是四秒钟
Not four seconds.
我三秒就能跑完
I could do it in three.
好吧  无关信息
Not relevant.
你没跟爱瑞丝说这些吧
You haven't said anything to Iris about all this, have you?
没有  我答应过你  我说到做到
No, I made you a promise. I keep my promises.
继续这么撒谎
Keep on lying like that,
你还会被闪电击中的
you're liable to get struck by lightning again.
现在就去实验室
Get up to the lab.
开始分析从枪械店拿回来的证据
Start processing the evidence from the gun store.
爱瑞丝  你好
Hey, Iris.
巴里又跑了
Did Barry run away again?
除非这个问题出现在你的家庭作业里
Unless that's one of your homework questions, little lady,
不然就不关你的事  小朋友
it's none of your business.
回你房间去吧
Go on back to your room.
我想见我爸爸
I want to see my dad.
巴里  我说了不行
I already said no, Barry.
他没做那些事  他没有伤害我妈妈
He didn't do those things. He didn't hurt my mom.
关于那晚我说的是真的  我看见了
I was there that night. I saw.
-当时有个男人  -我知道
- There was a man. - Yeah, I know.
我们已经谈过这个了
We've gone through this already.
那我为什么不能见他
Then why can't I go see him?
因为我说了不可以
Because I said so.
你不是我爸爸  你无权告诉我该做什么
You're not my father! You can't tell me what to do!
现在  我是唯一一个关心你的成年人
Right now, I am the only adult that gives a damn
所以我能告诉你你该做什么
what happens to you, so yes, I can tell you what to do.
现在回你的房间去吧
Now go to your room.
我恨你
I hate you!
这都是你的错
This is all of your fault.
我本来可以选修欧洲民俗学
I could have taken European folklore
来达到我的社会学要求  但我没有
to cover my sociology requirement, but no.
你跟我说  "爱瑞丝  学新闻吧
You said, "Take journalism, Iris.
当记者最有趣了"
Reporters have all of the fun."
你猜怎么着  巴里  当记者一点趣都没有
Guess what, Barry? Reporters have none of the fun.
新闻无聊死了  我现在好无聊
Journalism is boring. I'm bored.
都怪你  怎么了
I blame you. What?
你为什么这样看着我
Why are you staring at me like that?
你看起来真美
You look really nice.
谢谢
Thanks.
你为什么不好好打扮一下
Why don't you look nice?
今天下午  西装革履
This afternoon? Suit and tie?
学校要授予西蒙·斯塔格
The university is giving Simon Stagg...
-西蒙·斯塔格  -一个大奖
- Simon Stagg. - some big award.
-你答应我  -为了你的报道
- And you agreed... - To explain the science stuff
要给你解释那些科学知识  我现在想起来了
for your article. It's all coming back to me now.
你要多久才能回家换衣服
How fast can you get home and change?
一会儿就好
Pretty fast.
你好  艾伦
Hey, Allen.
乔让我过来看看你在处理
Joe asked me to see where you're at
枪械店证据的事情上进展到哪一步了
on the evidence from the gun store shooting.
你好  爱瑞丝
Oh, hey, Iris.
警探  你好
Detective.
得了  你们还是接吻吧
Please, guys, just kiss already.
记得吗  我已经知道了
I already know, remember?
谢谢你表现得这么淡定  巴里
Thanks for being so cool about this, Barry.
我知道保守一个大秘密不容易
I know it's not easy keeping a big secret.
我正在习惯
I'm getting used to it.
我觉得挺不可思议的
I find it quite remarkable,
年度人物  感谢他为器官移植做出的贡献
当年我还是中心城市大学
having once been a timid freshman
一名羞涩的大一新生
at Central City University,
现在我已经站在你们面前
to be standing before you now,
成为丽晶选择奖的年度获得者
the Regents Choice for man of the year.
虽然我很荣幸能够接受这个奖项
While I very much appreciate the award,
但对我来说  真正的荣誉是知道
the real honor for me is knowing that
我在器官移植方面做的工作
my work in organ transference
能够给予人们第二次生命的机会
helps give people a second chance at life.
非常谢谢你们的到来
Thank you all very much for coming.
好了  先说重要的
Okay. All right, first things first...
西蒙·斯塔格的细胞克隆工作
Simon Stagg's work in cellular cloning
为将来的器官替代学科
has led to huge advancements
带来了巨大的进步
in the future of organ replacement...
记者在工作时可以喝酒吗
Are journalists allowed to drink on the job?
好吧  如果你已经不耐烦了
Okay. If you are bored already,
还是得等到我们了解
just wait till we get to the science behind
细胞再生背后的科学
cellular regeneration.
真怀念这种感觉  巴里
I have missed this, Barry.
感觉我们自打你从昏迷中醒来
I feel like we haven't spent any quality time together
已经好久没有这样待在一起了
since you woke up from the coma.
是的  这几周过得真疯狂  我知道
Yeah, I've had a crazy few weeks, I know.
我觉得你因为艾迪总是在回避我
I thought maybe you'd been avoiding me because of Eddie.
我知道你认为我和老爸的搭档约会并不好
I know you think it's wrong, me dating my dad's partner,
-我就是  -不
- and I just-- - No.
并不是这么回事
That is not it. At all.
斯塔格先生  我能否引用您的话
Mr. Stagg, I was wondering if I could get a quote
来为我的报道添色
from you for my article.
现在不行  小姐
Not now, miss.
我还是自己编点东西吧
I'll just make something up.
你要跟我说什么
So... what were you gonna tell me?
你看起来好像要说什么重要的事
You looked like you were about to say something.
没错...
Yeah--
安静  所有人
Quiet down! All of you!
天呐
Oh, my god.
安静
Quiet!
想得多周到啊
How considerate!
你们都戴着最昂贵的首饰
You're all wearing your finest jewelry!
好像知道我们要打劫你们一样
Almost like you knew we were coming to rob you!
所有人排队站好
Now everybody line up!
不要  不要
Don't. Don't.
不许动
Freeze!
放下武器
D-d-drop your weapons!
闪电侠
巴里
Barry.
Barry!
我转过身来你就不见了
I turned around and you were gone.
发生什么事了  你没事吧
What happened? Are you okay?
是的  我没事
Yeah, yeah, I'm fine. I...
我跟着他们  想看清车牌
I went after them to try and get the plates.
-什么  -然后我就...
- Wha--? - And I...
我晕倒了
I fainted.
-你好  -爱瑞丝
- Hi. - Iris.
你们去哪了
Where were you?
爸爸  别紧张
Dad, go easy.
我在外面找到他的  他晕倒了
I found him outside. He fainted.
需要帮你找个医护人员吗  艾伦
You want me to get you a paramedic, Allen?
不用  我没事  谢谢  艾迪
No, I'm fine. Thanks, Eddie.
我以为我死定了
I thought I was dead.
我看到子弹发射出来  然后就嘣一声
I saw the gun go off, and then-- boom.
瞬间我就到外面了
Suddenly I'm outside.
我根本不知道是怎么到外面的
I have no idea how I got there.
你过来跟我谈一下
Let me talk to you for a second.
好的
Yeah.
你去追那几个劫匪了  是吗
You chased those gunmen, didn't you?
是的  那几个劫匪
Yeah, they must be the same guys
一定就是前几天打劫枪店的人
that knocked over the gun shop earlier today.
如果你抓到他们了  打算怎么做
And what were you going to do when you caught them?
请求他们乖乖地停到路边吗
Ask them nicely to pull over?
你并不是刀枪不入
You're not bulletproof.
等等  你是吗
Wait. Are you?
-不是  但是...  -那好
- No, but-- - Okay.
不许再逞英雄
No more heroics.
抓坏人不是你的工作
Chasing bad guys is not your job.
是我的工作  你不是警察
It's mine. You're not a cop.
跟我保证
Promise me.
我保证
Promise.
你知道爱瑞丝可不是傻子
And you know Iris is not stupid.
编点比"我晕倒了"更好一点的借口
Start making better excuses than "I fainted."
我...
I...
你骗了我们
You lied to us.
怎么不告诉我们你有阵发性晕眩呢
How could you not tell us you're experiencing dizzy spells?
我们是你的医生
We're your doctors.
天知道你身体内到底怎么了
God knows what's going on inside your body.
你的细胞处在不断变化当中
Your cells are in a constant state of flux.
你有可能会心肺衰竭
You could be experiencing cardiopulmonary failure
或者短暂性脑缺血
or a transient ischemic attack.
小中风  也可能不会
Mini stroke. Probably not.
在所有人当中你应该知道  科学要共享
You of all people should know that in science, we share.
我们之间不能有秘密
We do not keep secrets.
除了罗尼  还没有别人让她这么生气
Wow... I haven't seen anyone make her that angry since Ronnie.
罗尼是凯特琳的未婚夫吗
Ronnie was Caitlin's fiance?
加速器爆炸那晚死的那个吗
The one that died the night of the accelerator explosion?
是的  他...
Yeah. He is...
失踪了
missed.
现在...
Now...
我们看看你身上到底发生了什么
Let's figure out why this is happening to you.
尖端科研实验室
我们都准备好了
We're all set.
做点预防措施  以防万一
A little padding. Just in case.
好
Yeah.
你确定要这样做吗  西斯科
You're sure about this, Cisco?
大多数家用跑步机最大速度
Most home treadmills have a maximum speed of about
只能达到每小时12英里
12 miles per hour.
这个被西斯科改造了  相信我
This one has been Cisco'ed. Trust me.
它能承受你的速度
It can handle your speed.
好的
Okay.
心跳  血压  神经传导都很正常
Heart rate, blood pressure, nerve conduction all normal.
对巴里来说
For Barry.
脑电波在标准限额活动
Brainwave function within standard limits.
我说过这台跑步机可以承受的
I told you the treadmill could take it.
凯特琳
Caitlin.
看他的血糖值
Look at the glucose levels.
天哪  这就说得通了
Oh, my god. Of course.
-对吧  -这么明显
- Right? - It was so obvious.
血糖值  巴里
Glucose levels. Barry!
我们知道你为什么经常...
We think we know why you keep--
晕倒了
passing out.
警局
巴里
Barry!
杀妻案
诺拉·艾伦之死
巴里去哪里了
Where's Barry?
在洗澡
Taking a shower.
下午三点洗澡吗
At three o'clock in the afternoon?
如果我上楼  会看到巴里·艾伦吗
If I go up those stairs, am I gonna see Barry Allen?
或者你会因为撒谎而被禁足一周
Or are you gonna be grounded for a week for lying to me?
对不起  爸爸
I'm sorry, daddy.
别担心  我知道他去哪里了
But don't worry. I know where he went.
我也知道
Me too.
我又晕倒了吗
I passed out again?
急性低血糖
Total metabolic failure
导致的新陈代谢衰竭
brought on by acute hypoglycemia.
我吃得不够
I'm not eating enough.
输一袋葡萄糖就没事了吗
So an I.V. bag and I'm good to go?
四十袋还差不多
Try 40.
看来你是渴了
Guess you were thirsty.
我们得根据你的代谢变化
We're gonna need to fashion you a new diet
为你设计新的食谱
based on your metabolic changes.
我计算了一下  你需要进食
I've done a few calculations. You need to consume
将近850个墨西哥卷饼
an amount equal to roughly 850 tacos.
除非你直接吃牛油果蘸芝士
Unless we're talking cheese and guac,
那样的话结果又会不同
which is like a whole other set of equations.
要想吃墨西哥菜  我推荐提托家
For Mexican, I recommend Tito's.
在布拉克纳街
On Bruckner avenue?
他们家的玉米煎饼最棒了
Best burrito in the city.
韦斯特警探
Detective West.
你怎么会来尖端科研实验室
What brings you to S.T.A.R. labs?
你不在你的实验室
When I couldn't find you at your lab,
我就开始调查
I started doing a little research.
原来最近出了一位红衣侠
Turns out there's been reports of a red streak around the city,
又是抗击强盗  又是救火救人
stopping muggers, rescuing people from burning buildings.
你没告诉他我们在合作吗
You didn't tell him we were working together?
乔  我可以解释
Joe, I can explain.
你在警察局已经有工作了  巴里
You already have a job in law enforcement, Barry.
我建议你回去专心工作
I suggest you get back to it.
别看我  我是支持你的
Don't look at me. I'm on your side.
警探
Detective.
我们都是为了巴里好
We all want what's best for Barry.
你要真是为了他好
If you wanted what was best for Barry,
就应该好好劝劝他
you'd try to talk him out of this lunacy
而不是放任他出去拿自己的命开玩笑
instead of encouraging him going out there risking his life.
你也看到了  有个人能控制天气
You saw a man control the weather.
警方要怎么对付那样的人
What are the police gonna do against someone like that?
那场爆炸事件之后
Since the accelerator explosion
我们怀疑还有类似他的人
we suspect there may be more like him.
你准备怎么做
And you're gonna do what?
抓他们吗
Catch them?
你疯了吗
Are you insane?
你以为跑得快一点
You think because you can run real fast
就可以无敌了吗  并不是
that you're invincible? You're not!
你还是个孩子
You're just a kid.
我的孩子
My kid.
我不是你的孩子  乔
I'm not your kid, Joe.
你也不是我父亲
And you're not my father.
我爸爸正在经受牢狱之苦
My father's sitting in iron heights.
还抱着满腹冤屈
Wrongfully convicted.
是你的判断失误
You were wrong about him.
这次你也判断错了
And you're wrong about this.
也许我没能力帮他
Now I may not be able to help him,
但是如果我能从着火的大楼里救人
but if I can save someone from a burning building
或者阻止一些持枪歹徒  我一定会出手
or stop some armed thieves, I'm gonna do it.
你阻止不了我
And you can't stop me.
别白费力气了
So don't try.
你觉得自己聪明无比
You think you're so smart.
你们都这样
All of you.
但是有些事情你们根本不清楚
But you don't know what you don't know.
我希望你们能在发生死伤之前
And I hope that you're clever enough to figure it out
尽快想明白
before somebody gets killed.
你的其他同伴呢
Where's the rest of your crew?
只有我
Just me.
你要干什么  布莱克
What do you want, Black?
我的要求依旧只有一个
The only thing I still want in life...
让你的老板死
Your boss dead.
你和你的队伍动作太慢不能怪我
It's not my fault you and your team moved too slow.
我告诉你斯塔格在哪  可没说会待多久
I told you where Stagg would be, not how long he'd be there.
我要知道他的全部行程
I need his full itinerary.
还有他办公室和家里的安保权限
And security access to his office and home.
做梦
Screw you.
我在安保行业可是有名声的
I've got a reputation in the security business.
我的老板被杀是一码事
It's one thing if my employer gets iced.
在卧室里被杀就是另一码事了
It's another if it happens in his bedroom.
你最好按我说的做  加瓦先生
You'll do what I ask, Mr. Java.
你没有军队  能把我怎么样
What the hell are you gonna do to me without your army?
我就是军队
I am an army.
警察局
你又要来冲我吼了吗
Come to yell at me again?
西蒙·斯塔格的安保主管昨晚被杀
Simon Stagg's head of security was murdered last night.
法医在现场收集了皮肤样品
The coroner took some skin samples.
但愿是凶手的
Hopefully they belong to the killer.
看看有没有匹配结果
See if you can find a match.
昨晚斯塔格的慈善晚宴遭到袭击不是巧合
Can't be a coincidence that Stagg's benefit was attacked last night.
我这就去询问斯塔格
I'm going to interview Stagg now.
-我跟你一起去  -你的工作在这里
- I'll come with you. - Your job is in here.
留下来搞定工作
Stay in here and do it.
-爸爸  -宝贝
- Hey, dad. - Hey, baby.
我要走了
Gotta go.
我爸为什么生你的气
Why is my dad mad at you?
工作上的事
Work stuff.
你为什么生我的气
Why are you mad at me?
我们本来要在吉特见面
You were supposed to meet me at Jitters
你要给我的文章提供一些科学背景资料
to give me some scientific background for my article.
结果我没去
And I didn't show up.
现在我得在24小时之内拿出一篇新文章
And now I have to come up with a new article topic in 24 hours
不然我的任务就无法完成
or I fail the assignment.
-爱瑞丝  -别说对不起
- Iris-- - Don't say that you're sorry.
我知道你有歉意
Okay, I know that you are.
我不明白的是你到底怎么了
What I don't know is what is going on with you.
我们在同一个屋檐下长大
We grew up one bedroom down from each other.
你真的以为我不知道你开心的样子吗
Do you honestly think that I don't know when you're happy?
或伤心  沮丧  迷失时的样子吗
Or sad or depressed or lost?
我再问你最后一次  巴里·艾伦
I'm gonna ask you one last time, Barry Allen,
你最好老实回答我
and you better be honest with me.
你到底...
What the--
你想知道我发生了什么事
You want to know what's happening.
我现在能高速移动
I'm fast now.
天呐  我很想告诉你
God, I just want to tell you.
我的感受
How I feel.
我对你的感觉
How you make me feel.
但是我不能说
But I can't.
你到底是怎么回事
Hell is going on with you?
这个问题我们还没说完
We are not done talking about this.
这是不可能的
That's impossible.
昨晚发生了一起谋杀案
There was a murder last night.
这些皮肤细胞属于凶手的
These skin cells belong to the murderer,
但这些都是初始细胞
but these cells are naive.
他们可以复制这些干细胞
Stem cells that they can replicate
分析完成
变成身体所需的任何细胞
and become any cell the body needs.
这些只有婴儿身上才会有
They only come from babies.
意思说你的凶手是新生儿吗
This means your killer is what, a newborn?
你真的认为有人要杀我吗
You honestly think that someone wants to kill me?
我们还不确定  斯塔格先生  但是
Well, we're not sure, Mr. Stagg, but...
在你受邀出席的典礼上发生了持械抢劫
an event you were being honored at was robbed at gunpoint.
而你的安保主管今天早上被人谋杀了
And your head of security was found murdered this morning.
我是科学家  慈善家
I am a scientist and a philanthropist.
我们几乎不是杀手的目标
We're not often the targets of assassins.
那这些诉讼案呢
Well... what about lawsuits?
你有大概二十起悬而未决的诉讼案
You got about 20 of those pending against you.
这是无法改变的事实  警探
It is a sad fact of life, Detective, that
当你赚了一大笔钱时
when you earn a lot of money,
人们认为可以来分一杯羹
people who haven't think they can take yours.
比如说这个人吗
People like this guy, for example?
丹东·布莱克
Danton Black?
Danton Black.
货物升降机
你把他解雇了  现在他要起诉你
You fired him. Now he's suing you.
很遗憾  我们的工作关系没能继续下去
Unfortunately, our working relationship wasn't successful,
但是我可以向你们保证一件事
but I can assure you both of one thing.
丹东·布莱克
Danton Black...
不是一个杀手
is not a killer.
他是名临床研究员  不是罪犯
He's a clinical researcher, not a criminal mastermind.
如果还有需要帮忙的地方  请联系我
Now, if I can help you in any way, please let me know.
我和你们一样  希望这些人尽快绳之以法
I want these people caught as much as you.
那就来吧
Then here we are!
趴下
Down!
队长  发生了什么事
Captain, what's going on?
晚点和你说  巴里
Not now, Barry.
一名武装枪手正在斯塔格工业制造骚乱
An armed gunman is shooting up Stagg Industries.
乔在那里
Joe's there.
把他带出去  我来掩护你
Get him out of here. I'll cover you.
准备好了吗  快走
Ready? Go.
快走
Go!
不
No.
不管你是谁  赶快投降吧
Whoever you are, give yourself up.
抱歉
Sorry.
我们哪也不去
We are not going anywhere.
除非西蒙·斯塔格死了
Until Simon Stagg is dead.
抱歉
Sorry.
这些擦伤已经快速愈合了
The abrasions are already rapidly healing.
是啊  我毫无还击能力
Yeah, I got my ass handed to me.
你把血都弄到这套衣服上了
You got blood on my suit.
有一些应该是属于凶手的
I think some of it belongs to him.
又是一个不友善的超能力者
Another not-so-friendly meta-human.
丹东·布莱克
Danton Black.
生物遗传学家  专门研究治疗性克隆
He's a bio-geneticist specialized in therapeutic cloning.
形成新器官  代替坏死的旧器官
Growing new organs to replace failing ones.
显然是斯塔格偷了他的成果并解雇了他
Apparently Stagg stole his research and then fired him.
我看到斯塔格能自我复制
I saw Black create duplicates from his own body.
真是讽刺
That's pretty ironic.
这人专门研究克隆
The guy specialized in cloning
现在他可以复制自身
and now he can make xeroxes of himself.
如果他在用自己做实验
If he was experimenting on himself
当他接触到粒子加速器爆炸
when he was exposed to the dark matter wave
所投放的暗物质波
released by the particle accelerator explosion--
来看看这位克隆队长
Meet captain clone.
别担心  我会再想个更帅气的名字
Don't worry. I'll come up with something cooler.
你要去哪
Where are you going?
乔说得对
Joe was right.
我被超能力冲昏了头脑
I'm in way over my head.
我的速度是快  但我不是战士
Yeah, I'm fast, but I am no warrior.
我一个超能力者都打不过  更别说六个了
Man, I could barely fight one meta-human, let alone six.
巴里
Barry.
我明白
I understand.
今天你失败了
Today was a setback.
但是每项伟大的事业都会经历挫折
But any grand enterprise has them.
不坠机几次  我们也无法飞上天空
And we can never learn to fly without crashing a few times.
这不是伟大的事业  威尔斯博士
This wasn't a grand enterprise, Dr. Wells.
这是个错误
This was a mistake.
爸
Dad!
抱歉  不能有肢体接触
Sorry. No physical contact.
五分钟  艾伦
Five minutes, Allen.
坐下吧  儿子
Sit down, son.
巴里  你怎么到这里来的
Barry, how did you get here?
我跑来的  乔不肯带我
I ran here. Joe wouldn't bring me.
-他不让我见你  我恨他  -别别
- He wouldn't let me see you. I hate him. - No, no.
别这么说
Don't--don't say that.
不是乔不想让你来
It isn't Joe that doesn't want you to come here.
是我不想让你过来
I don't want you to come here.
我不想让你看到我这个样子
I don't want you to see me like this.
你必须得放了他
You have to let him go.
我爸爸没有做那些事
My dad didn't do these things.
他没有伤害我妈妈
He didn't hurt my mom.
是闪电里的那个人
It was the man in the lightning.
闪电人杀了我妈妈
The lightning man killed my mom.
-巴里  看着我  -不是我爸爸
- Barry, look at me. - Not my dad.
看着我
Look at me.
你帮不了我
You can't help me.
明白吗  乔会在我出去之前照顾你
Okay? Now Joe's gonna look after you until I can get out of here.
你只要继续当爸爸妈妈的乖孩子就好了
You just be the good boy that your mom and I know you are.
爸爸
Dad?
警探  持枪人被控制住了吗
Detective, was the gunman apprehended?
枪手目前位置尚不明确
The shooter's whereabouts are unknown at this time.
英雄警察拯救斯塔格总裁
我们认为他持有武器并且极度危险
We consider him armed and extremely dangerous.
谢谢  问题到此结束
Thank you. No more questions.
干得不错  艾迪
Nice work, Eddie.
天时地利而已
Nah. Right place, right time.
不  你是今日的英雄
No, you were a hero today.
还有一个杀手没被中城警局逮捕
CCPD still has a killer on the loose.
我得回警局了
I should get back to the precinct.
你来这里是为了喝杯咖啡
So did you come here for caffeine,
还是为了来告诉我你到底怎么了
or are you finally gonna tell me what's going on with you?
斯塔格先生
Mr. Stagg,
我希望您重新考虑保护性监禁的事情
I wish you would reconsider our offer for protective custody.
丹东·布莱克杀人不眨眼
Danton Black has proven he is willing to kill,
而且他还有些  朋友
and he's got... friends.
相信我  他们都很危险
And trust me, they're all dangerous.
我增强了保卫  警探
I've increased my security, detective.
我倒希望布莱克来找麻烦
I hope Black comes looking for trouble.
因为他会发现麻烦很大
'Cause he'll find plenty.
说话真像一位慈善家
Spoken like a true philanthropist.
还是人道主义者来的
or is it humanitarian?
抱歉  我总是记不住
I'm sorry. I can never remember
你正在假扮的身份是什么  西蒙
which one you're pretending to be, Simon.
哈里森
Harrison...
不用起身了
Don't get up.
又是你的粉丝吗  博士
Another fan of yours, doctor?
我们能谈谈吗  警探
Can we talk, detective?
这么说你是对的了
So you were right.
巴里不是唯一的特殊人物
Barry's not the only one who's special.
今天这个想杀西蒙·斯塔格的人  可以
This guy that tried to kill Simon Stagg today, he could--
不断地自我复制
Replicate spontaneously.
我们知道了
Yeah, we know.
你知道巴里的事吗
Did you know about Barry?
当他刚进入昏迷时
When he was first in his coma
你来到医院  询问我
you came to the hospital, and you asked me
是否能够把他带到尖端科研实验室去
if you could take him to S.T.A.R. Labs.
你那时知道他的能力吗
Did you know what he could do?
我当时怀疑他已经被...
I had my suspicions that he was...
影响了
affected.
乔
Hey, Joe...
我从没有想成为某个
I was never looking to become the senior member
秘密犯罪打击小组的长老人物
of a secret crime fighting unit.
你和我都清楚
You and I both know
我们才是保护中城的真材实料
we are the only ones equipped to protect Central City.
也许我更想要保护巴里
Maybe I'm more interested in protecting Barry.
当然了  他已经被教育好
But of course he's all set to fly
与你一同赴汤蹈火
into the fire right along with you.
不  他没有
No, he's not.
不再是了  他退出了
Not anymore. He quit.
他没告诉你吗
He didn't tell you?
我还没见到他
I haven't seen him.
我肯定只是暂时的
Well I'm sure it's only temporary.
以我对巴里的了解来看
From what I know of Barry,
当他自己决定了什么事
when he sets his mind to something...
就没人能够说服他了
No one's gonna talk him out of it.
但是下一次他穿起战袍
But the next time he suits up...
直奔危险之处时
runs headlong into danger...
他会失败
he will fail.
为什么呢
Why?
他不认为自己有能力
He doesn't think he's capable.
疑惑
Doubt...
才是他真正的敌人
is his real enemy.
乔  不管外边发生了什么
Joe, not whatever's lurking out there.
只要你继续在质疑他
And as long as you continue to doubt him,
他就会继续自我疑惑下去
he'll keep doubting himself.
而且顺便一提
And for the record...
我也关心他
I care about him, too.
看起来你真饿了
Guess you were hungry.
缓解压力吧
Stress eating.
我是来道歉的
I came to say I'm sorry.
你是对的  我是有些冷漠
And you're right. I have been distant.
-没错  -像个混蛋
- Correct. - Kind of a jerk.
你应该多道道歉
You should apologize more often.
你挺会煽情的
You are really sensational at it.
那么  那天你想和我说什么来的
So... what were you going to tell me the other day?
我觉得我得做件事
I thought I had to do something.
做件我觉得很重要的事
Something I thought was important,
但是结果发现我对那事并不在行
but it turns out that I'm not very good at it.
可我对做你朋友很在行
But what I am good at is being your friend.
所以如果你需要我帮忙
So if you need help coming up with
-给你找个新话题来写  -我有一个了
- a new topic for your article-- - I found one.
我找到了一件让我特别感兴趣的事
Something that actually interests me.
我知道这听起来有些疯狂
I know this is gonna sound crazy...
这周网上把这事都传疯了
it's been all over the internet this week.
在大楼失火时
At a building fire...
银行被打劫时
at a bank heist...
还有那晚那些劫匪
even the other night when those robbers
红色尾迹
开枪射击保安时
shot at the security guard,
那保安说他被快速地转移到了外面
he said he was whooshed outside.
有什么在救这些人
Something out there is saving people.
我以为你想写的是新闻
I thought you were taking journalism,
不是科幻小说
not science fiction writing.
从我认识你开始
Ever since I have known you
你就一直坚信一切皆有可能
you have believed in the impossible.
如果你没有说错呢
What if you were right?
也许你母亲去世那晚的事你说的是对的呢
What if you were right about the night that your mom died?
尖端科研实验室
我说了  我不干了
Look, I told you I'm through.
我知道  但你得来一趟尖端科研实验室
I know, but you need to get to S.T.A.R. Labs
马上
right now.
-巴里  没事的  -怎么可能没事
- Barry, it's okay. - It is not okay.
布莱克在这  而他就只是站着
Black is here, and he's just... standing there.
这不是他吧
That's not him, is it?
这是他的一个复制品
It's one of his replicates.
你们怎么弄到的
How did you get it?
我培养出来的
I grew him.
我从你衣服上分离出了布莱克的血样
I isolated a sample of Black's blood from you suit
试着能不能触发体外培养机制
to see if I could trigger the in vitro cultivation process
以便研究布莱克的增殖
and learn how Black multiplies.
所以我把靶细胞嫁接上了蛋白凝胶
So I exposed the target cells to a protein gel,
结果它们开始自我复制
and they began replicating...
成了这样
into that.
他为什么
Why isn't he...
它为什么不动
it doing anything?
我们做了一个大脑扫描
We did a brain scan.
只有无意识运动机制有活动  别无其他
Involuntary motor functions are active, little else.
我们认为它只是个接受器
We think it's acting as a receiver.
没有布莱克  克隆体只是空壳
The clones are an empty shell without Black.
只要打倒真的布莱克
Shut down the real Black,
可能就能一次打倒所有克隆体
and you might shut them all down.
但我们怎么知道哪个是真的丹东·布莱克呢
But how do we know which one's the real Danton Black?
我是因为你自己出现的昏迷才想到的
That occurred to me given your own passing out.
布莱克的能力有限制  就像你一样
Black has limits, just like you.
要控制所有克隆体
Controlling all of those clones
肯定要消耗巨大的体力
must require a tremendous amount of physical strength.
所以显示出疲惫虚弱的迹象的那个
So, look for the one showing signs of weakness or fatigue.
就是本体
He's the prime.
这只是个理论
Just a theory...
但你也许愿意实践一下  艾伦先生
but one you might want to put to the test, Mr. Allen.
还有  我做了这些高卡路里蛋白块
Plus, I whipped up these high-calorie protein bars
以便你能维持新陈代谢
for you to keep your metabolism up.
还有其他的吗
Any more of them?
没了
Nope.
它怎么突然动了
Why did it start moving?
是本体
The prime.
我想应该是本体下了命令
My guess is, the prime is on the move.
它也收到了战斗的召唤
This one heard the summons to battle.
而我知道它们正被召唤去哪里
And I know where he was summoned to.
斯塔格工业
Stagg industries.
那赶紧呼叫警员啊
You should call it in.
警方没法对付此事
Police can't fight this.
像马登一样  布莱克的能力
What Black's become, like Mardon...
我应付不了
beyond me.
警方应该也应付不了
Maybe way beyond them, too.
唯一一个能应付的人
The only person it's not beyond
就是你
is you.
你需要这么做  我明白
You gotta do this. I get it.
所以就这一次  你就听我一句话吧
So for once in your life, do what I tell you to do.
去阻止他
Go stop him.
斯塔格工业
明早把结果给我  行吗
Just get me those figures by morning, okay?
站住  不许动
Freeze. Don't move.
你好  丹东
Hello, Danton.
再见  西蒙
Goodbye, Simon.
待在这儿
Stay here.
我知道斯塔格偷了你的研究成果
I know Stagg stole your research,
但即使如此  你也无权杀人
but that doesn't give you the right to murder.
你以为我就是为了工作复仇吗
You think this is about my job.
我是为了伊丽莎白
This is about Elizabeth.
我的妻子
She was my wife.
她患上了冠状动脉退化
She had a degenerative coronary disease.
已经在移植名单上许多年了  但是
She'd been on the transplant list for years, but...
她没有时间了
time was running out.
所以我既然没法儿给她弄到新的心脏
So if I couldn't get her a new heart...
你就想给她培植一个
You were gonna grow her one.
我马上就要成功了
I was so close.
可是斯塔格偷走了我的研究
Until Stagg stole my research.
就为了能获得荣誉
So he could reap the glory.
而我只能眼看着最好的朋友死去
And I got to bury my best friend.
现在
Now...
我已经孤家寡人了
I'm alone.
记住  巴里  找到本体
Remember, Barry. Find the prime.
他们人太多了
There's too many of them to fight.
巴里  你必须要孤立本体
Barry, you need to isolate the prime.
我做不到  这根本就不可能
I can't. It's impossible.
一切皆有可能  巴里  你教我的
Nothing's impossible, Barry. You taught me that.
你做得到
You can do this.
巴里
Barry.
巴里  你没事吧
Barry, are you all right?
我没事
I'm fine.
结束了
It's done.
坚持住
Hang on!
不
No!
别
Don't.
中城警务人员现在确认了
Central city police officials are now confirming
-前雇员丹东·布莱克  -我试图拯救他
- former employee Danton Black-- - Tried to save him.
他不想被拯救
Doesn't sound like he wanted to be saved.
有些人  一旦受伤了...
Some people, when they break...
就再也无法复原
They can't be put together again.
有些人却在治愈后更强大
Some people heal even stronger.
我希望如此
I hope so.
至少多元体
Well, at least Multiplex
不能再伤害任何人
won't be able to hurt anyone else.
我告诉过你我会想到很酷的名字
Told you I'd come up with a cool name.
我也许是那个穿着英雄服奔跑的人...
Yeah, I may be the one in the suit doing all the running...
但当我在外面帮助人
but when I'm out there helping people,
改变世界时
making a difference...
你们与我同在
you're all out there with me.
我终于搞明白了一点
Finally realized something,
我们都被那次的闪电击中了
we were all struck by that lightning.
肚子饿了吗
Hungry?
意大利辣香肠  橄榄...还有墨西哥辣椒
Pepperoni, olives... and jalapenos.
我想你应该会喜欢
Just like you like it.
谢谢
Thank you.
你搞错了
You were wrong.
这周我搞错了很多事
I have been wrong a lot this week.
你得说得更明确一点
You're gonna have to be more specific.
你说你一直被
You said that one of things driving you
不能帮助你爸爸的事困扰着
to run around out there was that you couldn't help your dad.
你可以帮他
You can help him.
我们可以
We can.
我们会找出
We're gonna figure out
那晚杀害你母亲的人或东西
who or what killed your mother that night.
然后让你爸父亲免受牢狱之灾
And then we're gonna get your father out of prison.
我们一起
Together.
乔  之前我说你不是我的父亲...
Joe, what I said about you not being my father--
巴里  我知道
Barry, I know.
我知道我不是你的父亲
I know I'm not your father.
你说得对  你不是
You're right. You're not.
你只是...那个让我吃得饱
You're just... the man who kept me fed
和穿得暖的人...
and in clothes...
每晚坐在我床边等我睡着
who sat beside my bed at night until I fell asleep
因为我怕黑...
because I was afraid of the dark...
教导我写作业...
helped me with my homework...
教我如何开车和刮胡子...
you taught me how to drive and shave...
还把我送去上大学
and you dropped me off at college.
对于我你做了很多父亲会做的事
Sounds a lot like a dad to me.
每个小孩都梦想当超级英雄
Every kid dreams of being a superhero.
拥有能力  拯救人类
Having powers. Saving people.
但没有孩子想到当自己是英雄
But no kid thinks about what it's like when you're a hero
却无法拯救人类时会怎样
and you're not saving people.
事实是...
Truth is...
其他的都没怎么改变
not much else changes.
你还是会痛  你还是会爱
You still hurt. You still love.
你还是会许愿期待以及害怕
You still wish and hope and fear things.
红色尾迹的新消息
红色尾迹出现在中城街道上
被红色尾迹从火灾中救出的家庭
红色尾迹又在中城出现了
你还是需要别人陪你度过这一切
And you still need people to help you with all of it.
某种程度上  那才是最美好之处
In some ways, that's the best part.
巴里  有辆装甲车在格里芬大街被劫持了
Barry, an armored car was just hijacked on Griffin Avenue.
你马上赶过去
Get your ass over there.
收到  其实...
I got it. Actually...
最美好之处
The best part?
是这个
It's this.
好吧...
Wells...
是谁让你进来的
Who the hell let you in here?
你在外边搞了场派对吗
You been having a party out there?
我想你已经看过电视新闻了
I'm sure you saw on TV.
我的一个前雇员试图杀死我
A former employee of mine tried to kill me.
有复制能力的前雇员...
Former employee with the ability to replicate...
跟能极速移动的人对峙
faced off against a man who could move at super speed.
你也看见他了  不是吗
You've seen him too, haven't you?
没错  看见了
Indeed, I have.
超凡的能力
Extraordinary.
他拥有的能力  就像...
The power he possesses, it's like the--
就像古代的神
it's like the gods of old.
就像地球上的神
it's like Mercury on earth.
你能想象如果你能控制他的能力吗
Can you imagine if you could control his power?
如果你能...如果你能驾驭它
If you could--if you could harness it?
你可能能改变人类的意义
You could change what it means to be human.
戴着红色面具的人是关键
The man in a red mask is the key,
我要抓住他
and I'm gonna get him.
戴着红色面具的人
The man in the red mask.
他叫闪电侠
He's called the flash.
至少这么说...
Or at least...
他有一天会成为闪电侠
He will be one day.
搞什么鬼
What the hell?
原谅我  西蒙
Forgive me, Simon.
我担心你会以为我是针对你
I worry you think that you will think this is personal,
其实不是
and it's not.
是为了那个戴着红色面具的人...
It's just that the man in the red mask...
世界上最快的人...
the fastest man alive...
必须确保他的...
he must be kept...
安全
safe.